STEPHEN BURNETT

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

SUMMARY

I am an inquisitive and diligent software engineer who has over six years of consulting experience. I have a passion for problem solving and learning. Consulting has taught me to live in a growth mindset where I strive to be better everyday. Working as a business analyst at Navitas Billing ignited my enthusiasm for coding and ultimately led me to pursue a career change. I strive to work for an organization that that is challenging and values growth.

SKILLS

- HTML
- CSS
- Javascript
- React
- Git
- Github
- SOL
- Express
- Ruby
- Ruby on Rails

CONTACT INFORMATION

CITY: Greater New York Area, NY PHONE NUMBER: (718) 510-4672 EMAIL: stephenburnett714@gmail.com

LINKEDIN: linkedin.com/in/stephen-burnett-01a63aa2

GITHUB: Stephenburnett714

Portfolio Site:

WORK EXPERIENCE

SOFTWARE ENGINEERING IMMERSIVE GENERAL ASSEMBLY | DEC 2019 - MAR 2020

Full time fellow in the Software Engineering Immerse program that includes over 400 hours of professional training over 12 weeks.

Education: Git, GitHub, Command Line, JavaScript, CSS, HTML, Ruby, Ruby on Rails, SQL, Express, and React.

BUSINESS CONSULTANT THE ACCELA GROUP | JAN 2013 - JUL 2019

Provided financial modeling, mergers and acquisition analysts and client support for financial advisory firm focused on the development of start up early stage ventures.

 $Consulted \ with industries \ such as, IT \ Managed \ services, Financial-tech, Haircare, Hospitality \ and$

BUSINESS ANALYST NAVITAS BILLING | DEC 2015 - OCT 2016

Creator of investment grade financial model used for initial seed funding. Conducted product demos to perspective clients for the company's custom billing platform.

Worked directly with the CTO to develop a custom reports for a Software as a service billing solution for the deregulated energy industry.

CODING PROJECTS

Joyce's Caribbean Restaurant

Created a restaurant application that allows users to log-in, with auth, and create a profile. Once logged in the user can order food from the given menu items with the orders being sent to the back-end. Utilized React, Ruby on Rails and CSS.

Budget-Redesign

Worked with a team of software engineers to redesign the Budget rent a car website based on the suggestions of a team of UX/UDI designers. Utilized React, Express, Github and CSS.

Movies-Database

Created an application which allows users to search for actors, movies, and tv shows. The site then render information on the search category and allow for clickable routes. Utilized React and CSS.

Random Jeopardy

Created a Jeopardy application that utilized JavaScript, CSS, HTML and a Jeopardy API which gives users random jeopardy questions.

EDUCATION

GENERAL ASSEMBLY SOFTWARE ENGINEERING IMMERSIVE

MISERICORDIA UNIVERSITY BACHELOR OF SCIENCE - HEALTHCARE MANAGEMENT